Guide to the J. E. Wallace Sterling, President of Stanford University, Papers
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Papers, Series 1
  - Pacific Coast Conference - Report of the Commissioner on Rules Enforcement, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Pacific Coast Conference - Report of the Commissioner on Rules Enforcement, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Pacific Coast Conference - Summary of Self Examination Reports, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Pacific Coast Conference - Report of the Commissioner on Rules Enforcement, 1957 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU), 1945-1950 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU), 1950-1951 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU), 1948-1952 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU), 1952-1953 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI), 1946-1947 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    Campaign to found and fund the institute
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI), 1948-1949 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI), 1949-1950 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI), 1951-1952 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI), 1951-1952 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI), 1952-1953 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI), 1952-1953 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI) - Minutes, Annual Report, 1948-1949 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI) - Minutes, Annual Report, 1949-1950 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1948-1949 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1950 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    Bids to build homes
  - Trustees, Board of, 1950 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1952-1954 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1953 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1953-1954 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1954 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1955 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Trustees, Board of, 1955-1956 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Trustees, Board of - Academic Affairs Committee, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Trustees, Board of - Academic Affairs Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Trustees, Board of - Academic Affairs Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Trustees, Board of - Academic Affairs Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Trustees, Board of - Academic Affairs Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Trustees, Board of - Academic Affairs Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Trustees, Board of - Academic Affairs Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Trustees, Board of - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Trustees, Board of - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Trustees, Board of - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Trustees, Board of - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Trustees, Board of - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Trustees, Board of - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Trustees, Board of - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Trustees, Board of - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1955-1956 Subcommittee on Women's Residences (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Trustees, Board of - Investment Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Trustees, Board of - Investment Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Trustees, Board of - Investment Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 47, Folder 27)
  - Trustees, Board of - Investment Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 47, Folder 28)
  - Trustees, Board of - Investment Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 47, Folder 29)
  - Trustees, Board of - Investment Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 47, Folder 30)
  - Trustees, Board of - Investment Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - Trustees, Board of - Finance Committee, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 32)
  - Trustees, Board of - Finance Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 33)
  - Trustees, Board of - Finance Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 47, Folder 34)
  - Trustees, Board of - Finance Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 47, Folder 35)
  - Trustees, Board of - Finance Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 47, Folder 36)
  - Trustees, Board of - Finance Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 47, Folder 37)
  - Trustees, Board of - Finance Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 47, Folder 38)
  - Trustees, Board of - Letters to, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Trustees, Board of - Letters to, 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Trustees, Board of - Letters to, 1951-1952 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Trustees, Board of - Letters to, 1952-1953 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Trustees, Board of - Letters to, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Trustees, Board of - Letters to, 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Trustees, Board of - Letters to, 1955-1956 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Trustees, Board of - Organization Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Trustees, Board of - Study of Trustee Organization, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on Land Development, 1951-1952 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on Land Development, 1952-1953 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on Land Development, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on Land Development, 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on Land Development, 1955-1956 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on the Medical School, 1952-1953 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    Sub Committee on Curricular and Clinical Teaching
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    Sub Committee on Facilities and Capital Costs
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    Sub Committee on Sources of Funds: Capital and Endowment Gifts
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    Sub Committee on Sources of Funds: Operating Costs
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    Sub Committee on Interim Operations and Relations
  - Trustees, Board of - Special Committee on the Medical School, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    Sub Committee on Funds: Capital and Endowment Gifts (Section on Individuals)
  - Trustees, Board of - Committee on the Medical School, 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Trustees, Board of - Committee on Planning and Development, 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Trustees, Board of - Committee on Planning and Development, 1955-1956 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Trustees, Board of- Agenda, 1949-1950 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - Trustees, Board of - Board of Governors, University Hospitals, 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - Trustees, Board of - Board of Governors, University Hospitals, 1955-1956 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Trustees, Board of - Committee on Hospital Administration, 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Ford Foundation - Individual Behavior and Human Relations program, 1950 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Individual Behavior and Relations program, 1949-1955 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    $100,000
  - Ford Foundation Grant - requests by Stanford faculty, 1927-1952 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Misc. expired grants, 1954-1959 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Includes listing of Ford grants to Stanford as of 9/15/55 (20 grants totaling 1.8 million dollars).
  - Ford Foundation Grant - ASSU pamphlet on foreign student's program, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Visiting Committee for the Stanford Survey of Behavioral Sciences, 1952-1955 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Visiting Committee for the Stanford Survey of Behavioral Sciences, 1953-1954 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Visiting Committee for the Stanford Survey of Behavioral Sciences, 1953-1954 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    Material from Provost's Office, Committee
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Visiting Committee for the Stanford Survey of Behavioral Sciences, 1955-1963 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    Follow up to Survey, further grants
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Free University of Berlin Exchange Professor Program, 1952-1955 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Chinese Philosophy, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    Prof. John Goheen, Chinese language teaching
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Community Center, 1958-1960 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    Study of Little House- Hilgard and Schram
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Economic Research, 1956-1960 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Institute of Development Economics, Karachi, Pakistan, 1962-1964 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    $678,000 to assist the program
  - Ford Fund for the Advancement of Education - Stanford Center in Germany (Stuttgart), 1957 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    $15,000 grant, Alvin Eurich (interim Stanford president before Sterling) and Clarence Faust (former Dean of Humanities and Sciences) worked for the Ford Fund at this time
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Program in Engineering and Science, 1960-1953 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    $1.2 million for expansion of advanced graduate education in Chemical Engineering and Materials Science
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Faculty Salary Increases, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Faculty Salary Increases, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Faculty Salary Increases, 1955-1956 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    see also College Grants Program; Ford Foundation started with $50 million which went to various schools as "Accomplishment Grants." In December 1955 they announced another $210 million available for "Endowment Grants." Stanford got $3.3 million.
  - Ford Fund for the Advancement of Education - Faculty Fellowship Program, 1951-1956 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Stanford Study of Undergraduate Education, 1954-1955 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Professor Philip W. Buck, 1954-1959 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    Study of British politics
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Far Eastern Studies student aid, 1955-1960 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    $3,800
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Professor Leon Festinger, 1957-1963 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    $50,000 for research in theory of cognitive dissonance
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Professor John Goheen, 1953-1954 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    $23,425 for study of Values, Decisions, and Rationales
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Palo Alto Hospital Temporary Buildings, 1956-1959 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    $129,000
  - Ford Foundation Grant - San Francisco Hospital Rehabilitation, 1956-1958 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    $173,300
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Medical Education, 1956-1957 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    $3.1 million for Medical School endowment
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Public Affairs Research Program, 1958- 1963 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    $50,000
  - Ford Fund for the Advancement of Education - Faculty Fellowship Program Advisory Services, 1953-1955 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    $3,000
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Hoover Institute and Library, 1952-1959 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    $225,000 to process materials on China, Japan, Near East
  - Ford Foundation Grant- Dr. Robert Sears and Ernest Hilgard, 1955-1959 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    $300,000 for research on personality dynamics and development
  - Ford Fund for the Advancement of Education - Graduate Program in Humanities, 1951-1960 (Box 49, Folder 33)
    $235,000
  - Grant Applications, 1954-1962 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Grants Denied - General, 1954-1962 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Grants - A, 1955-1965 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Grant - Aerojet General Corporation, 1961 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Grant - Air Force Research, 1960-1963 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Grant - Alameda County Tuberculosis and Health Association, 1946-1951 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Raffel, Arroyo del Valle
  - Grant - Allstate Foundation Driving School, 1954-1960 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Grant - American Cancer Society: General, 1952-1965 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Grant - American Cancer Society: Tatum EG27A-D, 1949-1956 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Grant - American Cancer Society: Twitty CP13B-C 1947-1956 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Grant - American Cancer Society of California: Tumor Therapy Clinic, 1946-1960 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Grant - American Chemical Society: Misc., 1956-1964 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Grant - American Heart Association: Misc., 1953-1965 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Grant - American Medical Association: Misc., 1946-1964 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Grant - American Medical Association: Dreisbach 1952 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Grant - American Medical Association: Hultgren, 1949 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Grant - American Trudeau Society: Dr. Raffel, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Grant - Army Research, 1961-1964 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Grant - Asia Foundation: Misc., 1959-1964 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Grant - Atomic Energy Commission, 1958-1965 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Grant - Avalon Foundation, 1958-1962 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Grants - B, 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Grant - Barrett and Hilp Archaelogical Project (Gerow), 1952 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Grant - Borden Company, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    Anderson, John
  - Grant - Bothin Helping Fund: Cardiovascular Research Laboratory, 1948-1951 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Grant - Brookings Intitution, 1955-1957 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    Trends in Commercial Banking, Shaw
  - Grant - Burroughs Wellcome and Company, 1955-1964 (Box 50, Folder 27)
    Dr. Fishgold, "Myleran", pharmacology
  - Grants - C, 1958-1964 (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - Grant - California Research Corporation, 1953-1964 (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - Grant - California Scottish Rite Fund: Childhood Aphasia Program, 1962-1964 (Box 50, Folder 30)
  - Grant - California Tuberculosis and Health Association, 1952-1962 (Box 50, Folder 31)
  - Grant - California Tuberculosis Association, 1943-1960 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    Dr. Raffel
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Social Structure of Urban Communities, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 33)
    Dr. Bell
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: History of Higher Education, 1955-1960 (Box 50, Folder 34)
    $50,000 to W.H. Cowley
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Undergraduate Honors Program in Behavioral Sciences, 1958-1963 (Box 50, Folder 35)
    $107,000
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Economic Development of Africa, 1953-1964 (Box 50, Folder 36)
    $150,000 to the Food Research Institute
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Courses for Graduate Special Students, 1953-1960 (Box 50, Folder 37)
    $36,450
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Hoover Institute, 1947-1953 (Box 50, Folder 38)
    $180,000 for "research, training, and public enlightenment in international relations"
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Senior Colloquia, 1958-1963 (Box 50, Folder 39)
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Conference on Anthropology and the Educative Process, 1953-1956 (Box 50, Folder 40)
    $10,400 to Spindler
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Lewis Terman, 1951-1955 (Box 50, Folder 42)
    $11,000 for follow up studies of gifted individuals
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Stanford Center in Tokyo, 1961-1963 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    $134,000
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Undergraduate Field Training and Study Program, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 44)
    Proposal not accepted
  - Grant - Carnegie Corporation of New York: Evaluation of Undergraduate Education at Stanford, 1955-1956 (Box 50, Folder 45)
    $20,000
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace - Steering Committee, 1957-1960 (Box 50, Folder 46)
    Sterling was on Steering Committee
  - Grant - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace: Studies of World Community, 1952-1960 (Box 50, Folder 47)
    $7,500 to Dr. Harold Fisher and Prof. Adda Bozeman
  - Grant - Chicago Board of Trade: Trade, 1954-1962 (Box 50, Folder 48)
    Food Research Institute, Dr. Working, Dr. Gray
  - Grant - S. W. Childs Management Corporation: Lewis Terman, 1951-1953 (Box 50, Folder 49)
    Support for gifted children studies
  - Grant - CIBA Pharmaceutical Products, 1949-1951 (Box 50, Folder 50)
    Dr. Anderson
  - Grant - CIBA Pharmaceutical Products, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 51)
    Dr. Farber
  - Grant - Citizenship Clearing House: Civic Education, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 52)
  - Grant - Jane Coffin Childs Memorial Fund for Medical Research, 1948-1965 (Box 50, Folder 53)
  - Grant - Column Research Council of Engineering Foundation, 1949 (Box 50, Folder 54)
    Timoshenko
  - Grants - D, 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 55)
  - Grant - Danforth Foundation, 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 56)
    Dr. Alexander Miller
  - Grant - DuPont De Nemours and Company, 1957-1965 (Box 50, Folder 57)
  - Grants -E, 1955-1965 (Box 50, Folder 58)
  - Grant - Educational Facilities Laboratories, Inc., 1959-1965 (Box 50, Folder 59)
    School Construction Systems Development Project, Cubberley Auditorium Renovation
  - Grant - ENDO Products, Inc., 1953 (Box 50, Folder 60)
    Dr. Kuzell, Dept. of Pharmacology
  - Grant - Engineering Foundation: Misc., 1959 (Box 50, Folder 61)
  - Grant - Engineering Foundation of New York, 1949-1950 (Box 50, Folder 62)
    Dr. Schellinger
  - Grant - Equitable Life Assurance Society, 1956-1960 (Box 50, Folder 63)
  - Grant - ESSO Education Foundation, 1956-1965 (Box 50, Folder 64)
  - Grant - Ethicon, Inc. and Ortho Pharmaceutical Corp., 1960 (Box 50, Folder 65)
    Dr. J. Garrott Allen
  - Grants - F, 1953-1964 (Box 50, Folder 66)
  - Grant - Fireman's Fund Foundation, 1955-1957 (Box 50, Folder 67)
    see also New York Life Insurance Co., Stanford Insurance Program - Business School
  - Grant - Mac C. Fleischmann Foundation of Nevada, 1952-1956 (Box 50, Folder 68)
    Cancer Research
  - Grant- Mac C. Fleischmann Foundation of Nevada, 1959-1965 (Box 50, Folder 69)
    $250,000 to Hoover Institution
  - Grant - Mac C. Fleischmann Foundation of Nevada, 1961-1962 (Box 50, Folder 70)
    $767,000 to Medical School
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Behavioral Sciences, 1955-1959 (Box 50, Folder 71)
    $50,000 to Schramm
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Behavioral Sciences, 1956-1957 (Box 50, Folder 72)
    $4250 to Spindler
  - Ford Foundation Grant - Behavioral Sciences, 1959-1961 (Box 50, Folder 73)
    $82,500 to Dr. Karl Pribram
  - Grants - G, 1958-1964 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Grant - Geigy Pharmaceuticals, 1953-1954 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Grants - General Motors Corp., 1958-1965 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Grants - General Electric Co., 1963-1965 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Festinger, managerial motivation
  - Grants - Generl Electric Company: Summer Fellowship Program for High School Math and Economics Teachers, 1955-1960 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Grants - General Foods Fund: Chemistry and Misc., 1959-1964 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Grants - General Mills: Nutrition Workshop, School of Education, 1948-1951 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Grants - General Mills Food Research Fund: Grain consumption since 1880, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Grants - H, 1963-1965 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Grants - John A. Hartford Foundation, Inc., 1960-1964 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Grants - Heckathorn and Compnay: Prof. Eastman, 1951 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Grants - Hill-Burton Funds: Application for Stanford Rehabilitation Facility, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Grants - I, 1959-1963 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Grants - International Business Machines Corp. (IBM): Misc., 1960-1963 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Grants - Inter-University Committee on Travel Grants, 1956-1961 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Grants - Inter-University Committee on Travel Grants: Arthur Voyce, 1958 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    Travel to USSR
  - Grants - J, 1957 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Grants - James Foundation of New York, 1944-1952 (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Grants - Jeremiah Milbank (J.M.) Foundation: Hoover Library, 1944-1954 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Grants - Mead Johnson and Company, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Grants - K, 1961-1964 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - Grants - W.K. Kellogg Foundation: General, 1949-1960 (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Grants - W.K. Kellogg Foundation: Educational Administration Program, 1950-1956 (Box 51, Folder 23)
    $180,000
  - Grants - W.K. Kellogg Foundation: Proposal for Continuing Education Center, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 24)
  - Grants - W.K. Kellogg Foundation: Continuing Education Center Material, 1955-1959 (Box 51, Folder 25)
  - Grants - W. D. Kellogg Foundation: Leadership Development in Public School Administration, 1957-1964 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    $225,000
  - Grants - L, 1959-1964 (Box 51, Folder 27)
  - Grants - Life Insurance Medical Research Fund, 1947-1951 (Box 51, Folder 28)
  - Grants - Life Insurance Medical Research Fund, 1948-1951 (Box 51, Folder 29)
  - Grants - Life Insurance Medical Research Fund, 1953-1964 (Box 51, Folder 30)
  - Grants - Lilly Endowment, Inc.: Hoover Institution, 1960-1962 (Box 51, Folder 31)
  - Grants - M, 1956-1965 (Box 51, Folder 32)
  - Grants - John and Mary R. Markle Foundation, 1949-1951 (Box 51, Folder 33)
  - Grants - John and Mary R. Markle Foundation, 1951-1964 (Box 51, Folder 34)
  - Grants - John and Mary R. Markle Foundation: Medical School Transition Fund, 1955-1964 (Box 51, Folder 35)
  - Grants - Medical Sciences Research Foundation, 1958 (Box 51, Folder 36)
  - Grants - Merck and Company, Inc.: Study of Vitamin U, 1951-1952 (Box 51, Folder 37)
    Cheney
  - Grants - Merck and Company, Inc.: Cortone, 1951 (Box 51, Folder 38)
    Farber
  - Grants - Merck and Company, Inc.: Misc., 1954-1964 (Box 51, Folder 39)
  - Grants - Merril Foundation for Advancement of Financial Knowledge: Speculative Prices, 1949-1952 (Box 51, Folder 40)
    Working
  - Grants - Midlake Drug Compnay, 1951 (Box 51, Folder 41)
  - Grants - Monterey County Heart Association, 1955-1959 (Box 51, Folder 42)
  - Grants - N, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 43)
  - Grants - National Academy of Sciences (NAS), 1955-1965 (Box 51, Folder 44)
  - Grants - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), 1959-1965 (Box 51, Folder 45)
  - Grants - National Defense Education Act (NDEA): Insititute of American History in Austria, 1965-1966 (Box 51, Folder 46)
  - Grants - National Council to Combat Blindness, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 48)
  - Grants - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1955-1961 (Box 51, Folder 49)
  - Grants - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1943-1954 (Box 51, Folder 50)
  - Grants - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1945-1951 (Box 51, Folder 51)
  - Grants - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1951-1952 (Box 51, Folder 52)
  - Grants - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1946-1964 (Box 51, Folder 53)
  - Grants - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1954-1962 (Box 51, Folder 54)
  - Grants - National Multiple Sclerosis Society, 1955-1964 (Box 51, Folder 55)
  - Grants - National Research Council, 1952-1955 (Box 51, Folder 56)
  - Grants - National Science Foundation (NSF): Training for High School Science and Math Teachers, 1956-1957 (Box 51, Folder 60)
  - Grants - National Science Foundation (NSF): Proposal for Econometric Research Institute, 1964 (Box 51, Folder 61)
  - Grants - National Science Foundation (NSF): Graduate Traineeships, 1965 (Box 51, Folder 62)
  - Grants - National Science Foundation (NSF): Institutional Grants for Science, 1964 (Box 51, Folder 63)
  - Grants - National Science Foundation (NSF): International Geophysical Year, 1956-1960 (Box 51, Folder 64)
  - Grants - National Science Foundation (NSF): Van de Graaf Accelerator, 1957-1962 (Box 51, Folder 65)